Welcome to the new feature introduction video of Marvelous Designer 2025.
Now you can convert the action files from other software or platform creation to the action files that match the default virtual model of Marvelous Designer.
Here I use the free files downloaded on Mixamo.
Search on the website and apply the action files you need.
Search for keywords in the search box, then double-click to apply the action on the website to the default model or the virtual model you uploaded.
Check all settings, such as arm space, etc.
Then click download, select the FBX file in the pop-up menu, and return to Marvelous Designer after downloading the desired option.
Go to the top of the main menu, and the virtual model is automatically converted into an action, then select gender in the window.
Here select the virtual model gender of the action.
After that, our action files can be stored and used for other virtual models, then open the downloaded FBX file and click convert.
Marvelous Designer will automatically convert the FBX file to a software-adjustable MTN action file.
It is a very convenient and easy way to convert the FBX file into a software-adjustable MTN action file.
The FBX file is a very convenient and easy way to convert the FBX file into a software-adjustable MTN action file.
When the conversion is completed, click the save button and select the save path.
Name the unpreserved action file and place it in the right place.
Then click on the bottom triangle at the bottom of the screen to open the animation editor.
In the play area, click the mouse button on the right to select the range to be limited to the activity frame.
This can set the starting and ending frames of the play area to the first and last frame with animation.
In the play area, click the mouse button to put in the first frame.
You will see a list of all the action files in the play area that I have created previously.
Go to the main menu and click on opening.
Click on the top line of the window.
Select the costume option and click OK.
Then, in the pop-up window, select the current virtual model size and posture option.
After wearing the costume, set the simulation quality to animation.
This setting will help you record more stable and accurate animation simulation data.
Click the record button and start recording the costume animation as the character moves.
When the recording is complete, check if the costume animation is correctly recorded.
Now you can easily use the external animation file.
The action file can also be used for a virtual model after joint printing.
Please check the following tutorial.